This is going to be a quick lecture to understand what is the need for retrieval, augmented
generation or RAG.
So if you see the biggest challenge with the foundation model is lack of proprietary information
or enterprise information.
So we know that the foundation models are trained on generic internet data.
So if you ask it a question that is highly customized to your organization or enterprise,
it will not be able to answer.
Second, so it does not have an up-to-date information post-training cut-off date.
So if you see any base foundation model that is available on Amazon Betterock, it will
have a training cut-off date.
So maybe it has a training cut-off date of December 2024.
So any information post that it will not be aware of.
So those are the challenges that RAG-based system tries to overcome.
So retrieval, augmented generation or RAG, equip foundation models with proprietary information
by fetching the data from the company data sources.
So it can also overcome the challenges of no up-to-date information post-training cut-off
date through external sources such as documents and so on.
Now let us going to understand this through an example.
So let us say we are trying to build an e-learning chatbot which helps employees learn AI
technologies.
Now let us say we have built a generative AI application only using the foundation model.
And employee now asks a question to the foundation model which says what is the RAG reference
architecture in my XYZ organization?
Now let us say this question goes to our generative AI application built on top of Amazon
in bedrock so Amazon bedrock is going to route this question to one of the foundation models
maybe let us say entroping in this case and entropic is going to return with the response.
Unfortunately I do not have enough contextual information to answer this question because
I do not know what is the RAG reference architecture for XYZ organization.
So it is going to come back with a generic answer or it is going to say it does not have
enough contextual information.
So that is where RAG comes into play.
Let us assume your data is in the share point where you have PDF documents related to
Amazon bedrock EC2 and some of the other services.
Now let us also assume you have organization Gen AI reference architecture repository where
you store the reference architecture for all the architecture patterns.
So now what we can do is the Gen AI application built on top of Amazon bedrock can integrate
with these knowledge sources within the organization then you can use the intelligence
of the foundation model but also integrate it with the enterprise data source to get
the contextual information and it also solve the second problem of the cut off date because
all these documents can have the latest information.
So even if the foundation model does not have the latest information it can retrieve it
from these documents or other external sources.
So now what is the RAG?
RAG is the process of optimizing the output of a large language model by supplementing
the knowledge of a large language model with internal organization data source.
Okay, so that is pretty much it from this lecture.
I will see in the next lecture.
Thank you.